[Music]
first snow last night it's the 29th of
november so we thought it was about time
that we put our first christmas video
out for this year and it
is christmas pudding
ice cream
it's surprisingly simple to make tastes
amazing
this is how we prepared the base
[Music]
so for this base add in your milk into
your pan just get that warming up gently
and then add in your sugars now what
we've done here is separated some of the
sugar added in our stabilizer give it a
good stir make sure it's combined add
that into your milk too that stops the
stabilizer clumping together
then add in your corn syrup i've used
golden syrup here
now we're adding in our cinnamon and our
nutmeg into our skimmed milk powder give
that a really nice stir and then make a
proper mess
adding that into your milk
get it nice and combined then turn off
the heat this is where we've added our
cherry brandy you can add whatever
alcohol you like once you've added give
it a nice stir
and then put it in your container and
add in your cream that will bring the
temperature down nice and quick
then you can put it in the fridge for a
good few hours to chill it down
once your ice cream base is chilled in
the fridge ready
take your christmas pudding again this
is just a small one from the supermarket
but it's got a really nice flavor
break it up into whatever size chunks
you like as you can see we've gone nice
and small here
take your base out the fridge get it
mixed up again that cinnamon and nutmeg
obviously it doesn't dissolve so it'll
settle most likely at the top give it a
good stir make sure it's all combined
again then put it in your machine to
churn
once that's churned to a soft serve
consistency you can then add in your
broken up christmas pudding
let that go for just another minute or
two take it out and put it in a
container
[Music]
so
look at that tub i don't if you can see
it properly in focus i'll put
a picture of it over the front there
it's a really fun little tub that my
wife has done again these tubs are
amazing everyone she does is really
really great so i'm very appreciative of
her doing them because i tried one and
failed miserably
so let's get some scooped up and we'll
show you what it looks like
first things first
i don't really like christmas pudding
a bit pointless making this i guess
but
in this ice cream or in ice cream in
general christmas pudding really works
because you've got the sweetness of the
different fruits that go through there's
usually some kind of alcohol that's in
there as well
this i've just boosted some of those
flavors with a little bit of cinnamon a
little bit of nutmeg and then that
cherry brandy on top to really
give it a bit of a wallop but
it smells amazing let's just dive right
in and see what it actually tastes like
[Music]
it's amazing it's incredible it's really
soft really really smooth
now if you use a stabilizer just be
careful how much you use because you're
adding alcohol into this and that's good
advice for any time you add alcohol to
ice creams is watch the sugars the
alcohol and the stabilizer
they can sometimes get a little bit out
of control and before you know it you've
got too much sugar too much alcohol and
it just won't freeze but this
it's a really nice balanced ice cream
great flavor really really nice flavor
considering i just used a small
christmas pudding
there's loads of that flavor come
through and that's because i've added
the cinnamon and the nutmeg to it just
to really give it a bit of a punch but
if you make this after christmas and you
had a christmas pudding
you know whatever the flavors were that
were in that try and mirror that into
your ice cream base as well
this is a great great flavor to kick off
the christmas period with
we've got a few
little additional videos that we're
going to do over christmas we're also
going somewhere for
to a nice christmas market and there's
an ice cream cellar there so we're going
to try some of their stuff too so
i hope you've enjoyed this one nice easy
one thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
[Music]
you